Asian American Center Records UA106
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Asian American Center Records
1980 -- 2019
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Asian American Center
UA106
7.46 Linear Feet 5 Boxes
1 Web sites
Arrangement
This collection is organized into three series: Office files, Web crawls, and Unprocessed accessions.
Custodial History
A report titled 'Campus Issues for the New Minority Asian American Students' and dated January 12-13, 1984 was moved to this collection from the Women's Center records, May 2011.
Biographical / Historical
The Asian American Center supports Tufts's Asian/Asian American communities and seeks to create a positive environment for their academic and personal development. It was founded in 1983, in response to a racial incident in which members of a Tufts fraternity had pledges yell racial slurs in front of the Asian American House, also known as Start House. For decades, Start House functioned as both residential Asian American student housing and as the Asian American Center, but the arrangement made accessing the space both difficult and intimidating for non-residents. In 2018, the Asian American House was relocated to Hillside Apartments, and Start House was fully designated for Asian American Center programming and opened to the Tufts community.
The Asian American Center recognizes and advocates for East Asian, Southeast Asian, South Asian, and multi-racial Asian peoples, cultures, and identities at Tufts. In addition to providing educational programs about the Asian experience in America, the Asian American Center offers resources to help Asian students successfully transition to college, learn about and participate in campus events and opportunities, and engage with their peers through social activities. The Center offers a wide variety of resources and events, including the Asian American Peer Leader program, tutoring sessions, guest speakers, and casual social gatherings.
The Asian American Center is one of six official identity-based centers at Tufts. Other such groups include the Africana, FIRST Resource, Tufts Latino, LGBT, and Women's Centers.
Conditions Governing Access
University records are closed for 20 years from the date of their creation. Records older than 20 years that do not pertain to student education, staff and faculty employment and Board of Trustees records are open for research.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains Asian American Center brochures, correspondence, clippings, photographs, posters, publications, and peer leader programs. In addition, there are web crawls documenting its web presence.
Student Affairs and Services; Student life; Student activities; Student activism
- Office files, 1995 -- 2005; UA106.001; 1.2 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series documents the administration and activities of the Asian American Center including correspondence, brochures, academic advising, field trips and events, peer mentoring, and Start House student housing.
  Arrangement
  This series is maintained in the order it was received from the Asian American Center. Generally, files are arranged in reverse-chronological order, with most recent files first.
  Conditions Governing Access
  20 years from date of creation.
  - Brochure for Center, 2004 -- 2005; UA106.001.001.00001 (Box 1)
  - Discover Boston!, 2004 -- 2005; UA106.001.001.00002 (Box 1)
    Empty folder
  - George's Island, 2004 -- 2005; UA106.001.001.00003 (Box 1)
  - Peer Leader Packets, 2004 -- 2005; UA106.001.001.00004 (Box 1)
  - Jessica Hagedorn, speaker, 2004; UA106.001.001.00005 (Box 1)
  - Faculty/Student Workshop Buffet, 2005; UA106.001.001.00006 (Box 1)
  - Jigna Desai, 2005; UA106.001.001.00007 (Box 1)
  - Bill Ong Hing, 2005; UA106.001.001.00008 (Box 1)
  - Field Trip - Exploring South Asian Communities in Queens, NY, 2005; UA106.001.001.00009 (Box 1)
  - Asian American Month, 2003 -- 2004; UA106.001.001.00010 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence/Memos, 2003 -- 2004; UA106.001.001.00011 (Box 1)
  - Yong Chen - Food as Marker of Identity, 2004; UA106.001.001.00012 (Box 1)
  - Christine Ho, "Mail Order Brides", 2004; UA106.001.001.00013 (Box 1)
  - Grace Shimizu - Internment of Japanese Latin Americans (DOR), 2004; UA106.001.001.00014 (Box 1)
  - Monique Truong, 2003; UA106.001.001.00015 (Box 1)
  - New Student Lists, 2003 -- 2004; UA106.001.001.00016 (Box 1)
  - Peer Leader Packets, 2003 -- 2004; UA106.001.001.00017 (Box 1)
  - Peer Leader Program, 2003 -- 2004; UA106.001.001.00018 (Box 1)
  - Programs & Events, 2003 -- 2004; UA106.001.001.00019 (Box 1)
  - Room Reservations, 2003 -- 2004; UA106.001.001.00020 (Box 1)
  - Academic Advising, 2002 -- 2003; UA106.001.001.00021 (Box 1)
  - APAHE Conference, 2002; UA106.001.001.00022 (Box 1)
  - Asian American Month, 2002 -- 2003; UA106.001.001.00023 (Box 1)
  - Asian International Students, 2002 -- 2003; UA106.001.001.00024 (Box 1)
  - Brochure for Center, 2002 -- 2003; UA106.001.001.00025 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence/Memos, 2002 -- 2003; UA106.001.001.00026 (Box 1)
  - Dan Bacalzo Performance, 2002; UA106.001.001.00027 (Box 1)
  - Discover Boston!, 2002 -- 2003; UA106.001.001.00028 (Box 1)
  - George's Island, 2002 -- 2003; UA106.001.001.00029 (Box 1)
  - New Student Lists, 2002 -- 2003; UA106.001.001.00030 (Box 1)
  - Peer Leader Packets, 2002 -- 2003; UA106.001.001.00031 (Box 1)
  - Peer Leader Program, 2002 -- 2003; UA106.001.001.00032 (Box 1)
  - Room Reservations, 2002 -- 2003; UA106.001.001.00033 (Box 1)
  - Asian American Month, 2001 -- 2002; UA106.001.001.00034 (Box 1)
  - Brochure for Center, 2001 -- 2002; UA106.001.001.00035 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 2001 -- 2002; UA106.001.001.00036 (Box 1)
  - Day of Remembrance, 2002; UA106.001.001.00037 (Box 1)
  - Discover Boston!, 2001 -- 2002; UA106.001.001.00038 (Box 1)
  - George's Island, 2001 -- 2002; UA106.001.001.00039 (Box 1)
  - Peer Leader Packets, 2001 -- 2002; UA106.001.001.00040 (Box 1)
  - Programs & Events, 2001 -- 2002; UA106.001.001.00041 (Box 1)
  - "She Wants to Talk to You", 2002; UA106.001.001.00042 (Box 1)
  - Academic Advising, 2000 -- 2001; UA106.001.001.00043 (Box 1)
  - Brochure, 2000 -- 2001; UA106.001.001.00044 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 2000 -- 2001; UA106.001.001.00045 (Box 1)
  - Discover Boston!, 2000; UA106.001.001.00046 (Box 1)
  - George's Island, 2000 -- 2001; UA106.001.001.00047 (Box 1)
  - Peer Leader Program, 2000 -- 2001; UA106.001.001.00048 (Box 1)
  - Start House, 2000 -- 2001; UA106.001.001.00049 (Box 1)
  - Asian American Month, 1999; UA106.001.001.00050 (Box 1)
  - Building Community Through Leadership Retreat, 2000; UA106.001.001.00051 (Box 1)
  - Brochure, 1999 -- 2000; UA106.001.001.00052 (Box 1)
  - Programs & Events, 1999 -- 2000; UA106.001.001.00053 (Box 1)
  - Peer Leader Program, 1999 -- 2000; UA106.001.001.00054 (Box 1)
  - Discover Boston!, 1999 -- 2000; UA106.001.001.00055 (Box 1)
  - Resource Booklet (Faculty/Admin.), 1999; UA106.001.001.00056 (Box 1)
  - Start House, 1999 -- 2000; UA106.001.001.00057 (Box 1)
  - Brochure, 1998 -- 1999; UA106.001.001.00058 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1998 -- 1999; UA106.001.001.00059 (Box 1)
  - Discover Boston!, 1998 -- 1999; UA106.001.001.00060 (Box 1)
  - Jeopardy, 1998 -- 1999; UA106.001.001.00061 (Box 1)
  - Orientation, 1998 -- 1999; UA106.001.001.00062 (Box 1)
  - Peer Leader Program, 1998 -- 1999; UA106.001.001.00063 (Box 1)
  - Presentation Materials, 1998 -- 1999; UA106.001.001.00064 (Box 1)
  - Programs & Events, 1998 -- 1999; UA106.001.001.00065 (Box 1)
  - Start House, 1998 -- 1999; UA106.001.001.00066 (Box 1)
  - Asian American Month, 1997 -- 1998; UA106.001.001.00067 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1997 -- 1998; UA106.001.001.00068 (Box 1)
  - Day of Remembrance, 1998; UA106.001.001.00069 (Box 1)
  - Discover Boston! Orientation, 1997; UA106.001.001.00070 (Box 1)
  - Peer Leader Program, 1997; UA106.001.001.00071 (Box 1)
  - New Student Lists Orientation, 1997; UA106.001.001.00072 (Box 1)
  - Asian American Jeopardy, 1996 -- 1997; UA106.001.001.00073 (Box 1)
  - Asian American Month, 1996 -- 1997; UA106.001.001.00074 (Box 1)
  - Center Brochure Orientation, 1996; UA106.001.001.00075 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1996 -- 1997; UA106.001.001.00076 (Box 1)
  - Discover Boston! (Orientation Program), 1996 -- 1997; UA106.001.001.00077 (Box 1)
  - Peer Leader Program, 1996 -- 1997; UA106.001.001.00078 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Reception, 1996; UA106.001.001.00079 (Box 1)
  - Asian American Jeopardy!, 1995 -- 1996; UA106.001.001.00080 (Box 1)
  - Asian American Week, 1995 -- 1996; UA106.001.001.00081 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1995 -- 1996; UA106.001.001.00082 (Box 1)
  - Dessert Nights/Orientation, 1995 -- 1996; UA106.001.001.00083 (Box 1)
  - Discover Boston! (Orientation Program), 1995 -- 1996; UA106.001.001.00084 (Box 1)
  - Ethnic Groups, 1995 -- 1996; UA106.001.001.00085 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 1995 -- 1996; UA106.001.001.00086 (Box 1)
  - Peer Leader Program, 1995 -- 1996; UA106.001.001.00087 (Box 1)
  - Start House, 1995 -- 1996; UA106.001.001.00088 (Box 1)
- Web crawls, 2015 -- 2019; UA106.002; 1 Web sites
  Quarterly web crawls of the Asian American Community website crawled by DCA, as part of the Student Organizations web collection, to document the presesence of Tufts University student organizations on the web.
  Other Finding Aids
  To see all of websites crawled as part of the Student Organizations web collection, please visit https://archive-it.org/collections/6387
  - Asian American Community, 2015 -- 2020; UA106.002.00001; Asian American Center
    Open for research.
    General
    Frequency: quarterly crawl.
- Additional accessions, 1980 -- 2008; UA106.003
  - Brochures and Peer Leader Programs, 1996 -- 2002; UA106-001 (Box data_value_missing_5c69dce4f70f00e7ec2506af5cc16636, Box 1)
  - Student organizations, publications, papers and Center history and clippings, 1980 -- 2008; UA106-002 (Box data_value_missing_f5ed0c19537d3104e7b82658196498e0, Box 2)
  - Student publications and plaque, 1980 -- 2008; UA106-003 (Box data_value_missing_8161ecc029774a948f6bd8f2af8c2c2b, Box 3)
  - Posters and photos, 1980 -- 2008; UA106-004 (Box data_value_missing_498791eb98799a80c7fccaa8409ea9a6, Box 4)